Ever wonder what your life would be like with
different parents? A boy named North did.
North is a comedy, family, fantasy film directed by Rob Reiner.
Eleven-year-old North has had it with his parents.
They are always busy with their careers and don't give North the
attention he needs, so he files a lawsuit against them.
The judge rules that North should either find new parents or
return to his own parents within two months.
Thus North starts off on a journey around the world to
find parents that really care about him.
North, played by Elijah Wood.
Narrator (voice), played by Bruce Willis.
North's Dad, played by Jason Alexander.
North's Mom, played by Julia Louis-Dreyfus.
Arthur Belt, played by Jon Lovitz.
Judge Buckle, played by Alan Arkin.
North is a 1994 American comedy-drama adventure film directed by Rob Reiner.
The story is based on the 1984 novel North: The Tale of a 11-Year-Old Boy Who Becomes a Free Agent and Travels the World in
Search of the Perfect Parents by Alan Zweibel, who co-wrote the screenplay and has a minor role in the film.
The cast includes Elijah Wood in the title role, with Jon Lovitz, Jason Alexander, Alan Arkin, Dan Aykroyd, Kathy
Bates, Faith Ford, Graham Greene, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Reba McEntire, John Ritter, and Abe Vigoda.
Bruce Willis narrates and plays several different roles throughout the film, and a
9-year-old Scarlett Johansson appears briefly in her film debut.
This was the final theatrical film for Alexander
Godunov before his death the following year.
The film was shot in Hawaii, Alaska, California,
South Dakota, New Jersey, and New York.
It was produced by Castle Rock Entertainment and New Line Cinema
and released by Columbia Pictures on July 22, 1994.
North was a box office bomb, grossing $12 million
against its $40 million budget.
North was panned by critics, and has been referred to
as one of the worst films ever made.
The film explores themes of parent child relationship, child
prodigy, young boy, travel, based on children's book.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.